Guide to the Harrison Lee papers, 1928-1992 MS2011
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Wah Luck House, 1977-1982; MS2011 Series 3; 2 Linear feet
  - Proposed lease form, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - List of Chinese families displaced by convention center, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - On Luck House, San Francisco (similar development), undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Tenants' activities, n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous peripheral projects and concerns of the Chinese community in Washington, 1974-1989; MS2011 Series 4; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series consists of materials on the 1976 Bicentennial Celebration, Chinatown Gate (Chinatown Friendship Archway, Downtown Commercial and Residential Historic Districts, East West Center (also the Far East Trade Center), Gallery Place METRO, Lunar New Year Celebration, the Minority Contracting Act and Techworld. The material in this collection dates from 1974-89.
  - Bicentennial of 1976: Bicentennial Parade, Taiwanese Dragon, logistics, photographs, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Bicentennial of 1976: Bicentennial News (re Local Heritage Projects, 1976), undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Bicentennial of 1976: Chinese American Wall Mural, 1976 (funded by the Office of Bicentennial Programs, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Bicentennial of 1976: Bicentennial Ethnic/Racial Council Conference Report, 1974 June 27-28 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Bicentennial of 1976: Bicentennial Ethnic/Racial Coalition, Interim Steering Committee, 1974 October 08-09 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Bicentennial of 1976: Bicentennial Ethnic/Racial Conference Report, 1975 January 20-22 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Bicentennial of 1976: Bicentennial Ethnic/Racial Council, Executive Committee Meeting, 1975 May 30 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Bicentennial of 1976: Bicentennial Ethnic/Racial Alliance Program Guidelines, June, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Chinatown Gate (Friendship Arch): "Chinatown Gateway: A Proposal of Giving D.C. Chinatown An Identity," Chinese Consolidated Benevolent Association, 1984 December (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Chinatown Gate (Friendship Arch): Letter opposing People's Republic Arch, June, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Chinatown Gate (Friendship Arch): Similar arches and gates, photographs and newspaper articles re gates in Chicago, Los Angeles, Portland, etc.), undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Chinatown Gate (Friendship Arch): Dedication Ceremony, Invitations and Program, 1986 November 20 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Chinatown Gate (Friendship Arch): "Chinatown Archway at the Center of New Hotel Development," D.C. Office of Planning News, 1986 December (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Chinatown Gate (Friendship Arch): Chinatown Archway. Newspaper Clippings, 1984-1986 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Chinatown Gate (Friendship Arch): Correspondence, n.d., undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Chinatown Lunar New Year Celebration, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Chinatown Lunar New Year Celebration, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Chinatown Lunar New Year Celebration, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Chinatown Lunar New Year Celebration, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Chinatown Lunar New Year Celebration, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Chinatown Lunar New Year Celebration, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Chinatown Lunar New Year Celebration, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: Background. "Downtown Survey Completed..." Don't Tear It Down. April, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: Correspondence. Don't Tear It Down to Harrison Lee, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: Downtown Residential Historic District. Application for Historic District Status. 1981 Prepared by the Joint Committee on Landmarks for the National Capitol, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: Downtown Commercial Historic District. Application for Historic District Status. 1981. Prepared by the Joint Committee on Landmarks for the National Capitol, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: Request for Postpone of Public Hearing for Downtown Residential Historic District. Joint Comm. On Landmarks for the National Capitol (with letters in support), 1981 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: Testimony from Chinese Consolidated Benevolent Assoc., opposing historic designation, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: Statement from John McKoy, of D.C. Planning and Development. Statement on merits and deficiencies of application for Downtown Residential Historic District. March, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: D.C. Historic Preservation Division. "Introduction to Historic Preservation Processes Under D.C. Law." n.d., undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: U.S. Joint Committee on Landmarks of the National Capital. Decision recommending nomination of Downtown Historic District. July, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: Statement from John McKoy of D.C. Planning and Development. Statement on merits and deficiencies of application for Downtown Commercial Historic District. March, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: Halcyon Ltd. Final Recommendations on Preserving Small Buildings Downtown, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Downtown Historic and Commercial Districts: Newspaper Clippings, 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - East West Trade Center: Alley Closing Hearing, testimony and opinions, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - East West Trade Center: Conroy Co. Press release announcing development partnership. June, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - East West Trade Center: Prospects for Development (draft) and project overview, fact sheet, n.d. (Alfred Liu and Conroy Co), undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - East West Trade Center: Promotional Brochure Conroy Company, n.d., undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - East West Trade Center: Correspondence. Chinatown Steering Committee to Mayor, re community concerns re Development of Far East Center, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - East West Trade Center: Presentation (2nd) before Chinatown Steering Committee, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - East West Trade Center: Letters in opposition to proposal for Far East Center, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - East West Trade Center: "The Year of the Snakes: Chinatown Sinks its Fangs into Megadeveloper Mel Simon,"" Regardies, 1989 June (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - East West Trade Center: Newspaper Clippings, 1983-1988 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - East West Trade Center: Maps of construction site, Chinatown (including alley closings), n.d., undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - East West Trade Center: Notes by architect John Carl Warnecke, n.d., undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Gallery Place METRO Station; Gallery Place North Metro Site Joint Development Prospectus. D.C. Office of Planning and Development. August, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Pre-proposal Conference: Sign-Up Sheet, 1982 September 15 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Gallery Place. Proposal for Development from the Chinatown Development Corporation, 1982 November (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Misc. correspondence, 1975-1982 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Opening of Yellow Line. Ceremony, speeches, guest list, program, 1983 April 30 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Design Proposals: Chinatown Economic Development Corporation, 1982 November 08 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Design Proposals: Fairburn Organization, Inc., n.d., undated (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Design Proposals: Gallery Place Association, 14, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Design Proposals: Skidmore, Owings & Merrill, 1981 December 03 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Weaver Brothers' Bid, n.d., undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Gallery Place METRO Stop: Clippings, 1983-1989 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Minority Contracting Act of 1976: Minority Business Opportunity Commission. Minority Contracting Act of 1976/Act to extend to 1980 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Minority Contracting Act of 1976: D.C. Council Bill 3-253. Bill to Amend the Minority Contracting Act of 1976 {i.e. to exclude Asian Americans}, 1980 January 23 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Minority Contracting Act of 1976: D.C. Law 1-95 As Amended by D.C. Law 3-91. Minority Contracting Act {exclusion is legally enacted}, 1980 September 13 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Minority Contracting Act of 1976: Misc. Correspondence re Minority Contracting Law, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Minority Contracting Act of 1976: John Wilson introduces legislation to reinstate Asian Americans into Minority Contracting Act, 1982 March 18 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Minority Contracting Act of 1976: Letters in Support of John Wilson's Amendment, 1982 May (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Minority Contracting Act of 1976: David Clark's testimony before the City Council, 1982 May (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Minority Contracting Act of 1976: Minority Contracting Act Amendment. Asian American legally replaced in protected group, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Minority Contracting Act of 1976: Newspaper clippings on issue, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Minority Contracting Act of 1976: Minority Contracting. Press release for Linda Topping against Nadine Winter's proposal to limit the businesses of Asian Americans in Black neighborhoods, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Techworld: International Developers, Inc. Development Prospectus, 1983 October (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Techworld: Chinatown Steering Committee. Testimony for Eighth Street Closing, 1984 May 22 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Techworld: Techworld. Briefing Package. Press Releases, 1984-1985 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Techworld: Correspondence, invitations. IDI and Harrison Lee, 1984-1985 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Techworld: IDI, Report of Company Activities, 1983 May (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Techworld: Techworld Newsletters, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Techworld: IDI, Inc. A Decade of Important Developments, 1975-1985 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Techworld: IDI, Inc. Report of Company Activities, 1985 May (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Techworld: Techworld. Newspaper Clippings, 1984-1986 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Techworld: Grand Opening Celebration. Invitation, 1989 November 14 (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Printed ephemera, 1975-1992; MS2011 Series 5; .5 Linear feet
  This series consists of printed materials from the 1975-92. Major sources were the Washington Post, the Washington Times, the Washington Business Journal, and the Metro Chinese Journal, published bi-weekly in Cantonese in Silver Spring, Md. The series also includes newsletters from 1976-92, magazine articles from 1982-95, brochures and guidebooks 1974-90's. This includes D.C. Agency brochures (e.g. on Historic Districts, Using Zoning and Land Use Map) as we as government sponsored and commercial guides to Washington, and Chinatown.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Newsletters, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Newsletters, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Newsletters, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Newsletters, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Newsletters, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Magazine Articles: Moser, Charlotte, "Year of the Bulldozer: Future Looks Grim for Washington's Chinatown," Regardies, 1982 February (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Magazine Articles: Van Dyne, Larry, "The Excitement of Old Downtown," The Washingtonian, 1986 February (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Magazine Articles: Schindehette, Susan, "Chinatown's Chance," Dossier, 1987 May (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Magazine Articles: "The Year of the Snakes: Chinatown Sinks its Fangs into Megadeveloper Mel Simon," Regardies, 1989 June (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Magazine Articles: Fisher, Marc, "'If the Price is Right, We Sell': The Last Days of Chinatown,"Washington Post Magazine, 1995 January 29 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Magazine Articles: Richman, Phyllis, Stroffner, Robert, et. al., "Dining Out," "Cheap Eats," (articles on dining out in Chinatown), Washingtonian, 1985-1989 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Brochures and Guidebooks: Community Services Directory, (Asian-American), 1974 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Brochures and Guidebooks: Chinatown: A Special Place (draft and final publication), 1986-1988 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Brochures and Guidebooks: Chinatown--assorted guides, to restaurants, Lunar New Year celebrations, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Brochures and Guidebooks: Downtown Washington: Restaurant & Theatre Guide, 1990 Holiday Shopping Guide (take Metro), Calendar of Events, Downtown, D.C. A Walking Guide, undated (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Brochures and Guidebooks: General Guides, n.d. All About Town, See Washington by Metrorail, Washington, D.C. Conventioneer's City Map Guide, undated (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Brochures and Guidebooks: D.C. Government brochures: How to Use the District of Columbia Proposed General Land Use Map, Do You Own Property in an Historic District?, undated (Box 17, Folder 41)
- Awards and certificates, 1929-1984; MS2011 Series 6; .5 Linear feet
  This series consists of awards and certificates presented to Harrison Lee.
  - Small Accompanying Items: 2 chevrons, from the appointment to Corporal in Co G of the high school Cadets, 1929 May 10 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Small Accompanying Items: Ribbon, from the appointment to Captain of Co D 3rd Reg't of the High School Cadets, 1939 April (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Small Accompanying Items: Ribbon, from Eastern High School Diploma, 1939 June 21 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Oversized print documents: Certificate of appointment to Captain in the Company D, 3rd Regt of the High School Cadets, 1939 April (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Oversized print documents: Eastern High School Diploma, 1939 June 21 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Oversized print documents: Award of distinguished Cadet as a member of the Reserve officers' Training Corps, 1940 May 29 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Oversized print documents: Certified 16 hours of training in the management of housing for the elderly and list of all participants in seminar, 1978 November 20-21 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Oversized print documents: Certificate of Appreciation to the Downtown Plan, 1984 July 23 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Oversized print documents: Misc. letters to Harrison Lee, appointments, thanks, etc., undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Blueprints, undated; MS2011 Series 7; 1 Linear feet
  This series consists of one blueprint. Far East Center (7th St., NW between G & H){unbuilt} Architect: AEPA, 2421 Penn. Ave., NW Washington, DC 20037) Developers: Conroy Co. and Melvin Simon of Chinatown Development Corporation. Approximately 36 pages.
  - Apprx. 36 pp., Far East Center (7th St., NW between G & H){unbuilt} Architect: AEPA, 2421 Penn. Ave., NW Washington, DC 20037) Developers: Conroy Co. and Melvin Simon of Chinatown Development Corporation, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)